answering the age-old question if you
pop a human brain organoid into the
skull of a mouse does it change its
Behavior yes and this paper is so while
what they did in this adorable schematic
is took cells from people with Down
syndrome and people without and then
induced them to become the little brain
organoids and pop them in the skulls of
mice right onto their brains our little
brain friends are by the way almost
always made from donated skin tissue and
not fetal Drive these ones are made from
blood cells but back to what happens if
you want more brain for brain brain
squared if you're wondering how that
works you also have to know that the
brain organoids are quite invasive we've
discussed this before but they'll make
hybridized connections between even
different organisms between rats and
mice or human they're essentially at a
very very early stage in development
that means that they can grow and
develop connections that you might not
expect in an adult brain and no they
don't just take on the same structures
as their host they're still going to
look like the original organism that
they came from and that is our little
mousy forebrain after 6 months what they
found in these mice was overproduction
of og2 which is involved in the
proliferation of motor neurons so
overproduction of it could cause some
problems this gave them a target for how
some of the cognitive issues that we see
in people with Down Syndrome could be
treated but it goes much further finding
the up regulation or down regulation of
genes involved with cognition and memory
could help with other diseases and even
inform us of potential targets we're not
even aware of